<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="setting">pengaturan</string>
    <string name="identify_disease">Identify Disease</string>
    <string name="diagnose_from_gallery">Diagnose From Gallery</string>
    <string name="macam_penyakit">"Variety of Lettuce Diseases "</string>
    <string name="see_all">See All</string>
    <string name="jenis_penyakit">Type of Disease</string>
    <string name="nama_tanaman">Plant Name</string>
    <string name="delete">delete</string>
    <string name="image_plant">image plant</string>
    <string name="no_history_found">History not found</string>
    <string name="last_diagnose">Last Diagnose</string>
    <string name="benefits">Lower blood pressure</string>
    <string name="benefits2">Lower cancer risk</string>
    <string name="benefits3">Relieves cold and cough</string>
    <string name="benefits4">Streamline the digestive tract</string>
    <string name="healthy1">Watering can be done twice for newly planted plants. Watering is done in the morning and evening. Once the plants are mature enough, the frequency of watering is reduced to once a day in the morning.</string>
    <string name="healthy2">Fertiliser is only applied after the plants are 3–5 months old. The fertiliser is NPK (15–15–15), which you can find at farm shops. The fertiliser is given as much as 50-300 grams/tree. Further fertilisation can be done after the plant is 4 months old until the plant flowers. After the tree is 1-2 years old, apply NPK once a year after the harvest process ends.</string>
    <string name="healthy3">Wild shoots or water shoots on the tree should be pruned because they can interfere with plant growth. Pruning is also done when the tree has reached a height of 1.5–2 m by selecting three or four main trunks so that the crown of the plant is lush. Pruning of other branches is done 1-2 cm from the main trunk so that the pruning wound will not hurt the main trunk. Pruning is also done on old, dry, and unproductive branches.</string>
    <string name="healthy4">Prune unhealthy leaves and fruits</string>
    <string name="tes1_cause">Wilt and leaf blight infections in plants are caused by various pathogens, such as Fusarium sp. and Cercospora sp. fungi. The disease can be spread through soil, water, wind, as well as through contact with infected plants or unsterilised farm tools. Wilt is a condition in which the plant loses turgour or stiffness of the cells, so that the leaves and stems appear wilted and sagging. The main cause of wilt is infection by pathogens that attack the plant\'s vascular system, such as Verticillium or Fusarium fungi, which block the flow of water and nutrients within the plant. Early symptoms include wilting of the young leaves and shoots of the plant, which then spreads to the rest of the plant, causing defoliation and plant death if not treated promptly.</string>
    <string name="tes1_treatment">Prune the infected leaves to help the plant grow better.</string>
    <string name="tes1_treatment2">Regulating garden moisture can be done by improving drainage, pruning plants and shade trees regularly, and by controlling weeds.</string>
    <string name="tes1_treatment3">Dithane application is effective in controlling the disease.</string>
    <string name="tes1_treatment4">" Regularly clean hydroponic growing areas, such as containers and watering pipes."</string>
    <string name="tes1_treatment5">Use fungicides to control fungal infections.</string>
    <string name="tes2_cause">" Viral infections in plants are caused by various types of viruses that spread through insect vectors, such as aphids or thrips, or through direct contact between infected and healthy plants. Viruses can cause a variety of symptoms in plants, depending on the type of virus and the infected plant. Viral infections often result in plant leaves having yellow or mottled spots, known as mosaic. In addition, leaves may become curled, shriveled or deformed. If a viral infection progresses, the virus can spread to all parts of the plant, including the stem, which can lead to stunted growth and deformed leaves."</string>
    <string name="tes2_treatment">There is no direct treatment for plants already infected with the virus, but the use of insecticides can help reduce the spread of virus-carrying pests.</string>
    <string name="tes2_treatment2">Separate infected plants to prevent further spread.</string>
    <string name="tes2_treatment3">There is no direct treatment for plants already infected with the virus, but the use of insecticides can help reduce the spread of virus-carrying pests.</string>
    <string name="tes2_treatment4">Separate infected plants to prevent further spread.</string>
    <string name="tes3_cause">Caused by various types of fungi in the Erysiphaceae family. The spread of these fungi is mainly through wind-borne spores, flowers and fruits. Early symptoms are characterised by powdery white patches on the lower and upper surfaces of leaves. Infected leaves may turn yellow and die. Powdery mildew thrives in warm and dry climates/weather.</string>
    <string name="tes3_treatment">Avoid watering from above which may cause the leaf surface to become wet.</string>
    <string name="tes3_treatment2">Remove infected leaves to reduce the spread of the disease.</string>
    <string name="tes3_treatment3">Provide a minimum distance of 30–45 cm between plants to increase air circulation in plants.</string>
    <string name="tes3_treatment4">Spray fungicides such as sulphur at 7–14 day intervals to provide continuous protection to the crop.</string>
    <string name="tes4_cause">Caused by infection with the fungus Bremia lactucae, the spores of this fungus are spread by rain or air. This causes the leaves to have bright yellowish-green spots on the upper part of the leaf, while on the underside fine cotton-like hairs of a bluish-white colour grow. If allowed to develop, the fungus will penetrate into the stem which can cause the stem to rot.</string>
    <string name="tes4_treatment">Remove infected plants from the growing environment.</string>
    <string name="tes4_treatment2">Avoid watering from above which may cause the leaf surface to become wet.</string>
    <string name="tes4_treatment3">Increase air circulation to reduce plant humidity and provide adequate lighting.</string>
    <string name="tes4_treatment4">Avoid dense planting and control weeds, so that the air circulation around the plants remains good.</string>
    <string name="tes5_cause">Bacterial is caused by bacterial infections such as Erwinia carotovora, Felicularia F, Rhizoctonia S, or Xanthomonas spp. These bacteria can be spread through rain, splashing water, insects, or direct contact between infected and healthy plants. The optimum temperature for infection is 73°F (23°C). However, the disease occurs at warmer temperatures on lettuce grown in greenhouses. Bacterial blight often affects the leaves of plants with the appearance of small brown spots surrounded by a yellow halo, which over time can develop into large irregular blotches.</string>
    <string name="tes5_treatment">Arrange the spacing so that the outer leaves do not touch each other.</string>
    <string name="tes5_treatment2">Provide adequate lighting, with direct sunlight for at least 4–6 hours per day.</string>
    <string name="tes5_treatment3">Remove infected leaves to reduce the spread of the disease.</string>
    <string name="tes5_treatment4">Spray with pesticides containing copper hydroxide or a mixture of copper and mankozeb at intervals of 3–5 days.</string>
    <string name="tes6_cause">Caused by the pathogen Septoria lactucae, the disease spreads through water, wind, insect transmission, weeds around the plant, or even through human hands or tools. Infected leaves have light brown coloured spots that appear between the leaf veins. Affected leaves may dry out and become thin.</string>
    <string name="tes6_treatment">Remove seedlings that show leaf spots before transplanting into hydroponic media.</string>
    <string name="tes6_treatment2">Avoid wetting the leaves by watering from above.</string>
    <string name="tes6_treatment3">Clear the weeds around the plants.</string>
    <string name="tes6_treatment4">Increase adequate air circulation.</string>
    <string name="tes6_treatment5">Spray plants with fungicides containing copper-based ingredients such as copper diammonia diacetate.</string>
    <string name="link">Read More</string>
    <string name="titleArticle">Article Title</string>
    <string name="image_placeholder">Image placeholder</string>
    <string name="please_insert_a_picture_of_lettuce">Please insert a picture of lettuce</string>
    <string name="more_article">See Article</string>
    <string name="disease_lettuce">Lettuce Diseases</string>
    <string name="types_of_diseases_in_lettuce">Types of diseases in lettuce</string>
    <string name="article_image">article image</string>
    <string name="lettuce_disease">Lettuce Disease</string>
    <string name="image_classifier_failed">Failure classification</string>
    <string name="hasil_analisis">analysis results\n</string>
    <string name="result">Result</string>
    <string name="simpan">Save</string>
    <string name="deskripsi">Description</string>
    <string name="try_again">Coba Lagi</string>
    <string name="undefine">Unfortunately, our application cannot detect the image you have, please repeat again if the image does not match the symptoms.</string>
    <string name="manfaat_selada">Benefits of Lettuce</string>
    <string name="manfaat_healthy">1. Lower blood pressure\n2. Lower cancer risk\n3. Relieves flu and cough\n4. Improves digestive tract</string>
    <string name="tips_perawatan_healthy">1. Watering can be done twice for newly planted plants. Watering is done in the morning and evening. Once the plants are mature enough, the frequency of watering is reduced to once a day in the morning.\n2. Regulation of garden moisture can be done by improving drainage, pruning plants and shade trees regularly, and by controlling weeds.\n3. Fertiliser is only applied after the plants are 3-5 months old. The fertiliser is NPK (15-15-15), which you can find at farm shops. The fertiliser is given as much as 50-300 grams/tree. Further fertilisation can be applied after the plant is 4 months old until the plant flowers. After the tree is 1-2 years old, apply NPK once a year after the harvest process ends.\n4. Wild shoots or water shoots on the tree should be pruned as they can interfere with plant growth. Pruning is also done when the tree has reached a height of 1.5-2 m by selecting three or four main trunks so that the crown of the plant is lush. Pruning of other branches is done 1-2 cm from the main trunk so that the pruning wound will not hurt the main trunk. Pruning is also done on old, dry, and unproductive branches.\n5. Prune unhealthy leaves and fruits.</string>
    <string name="tips_perawatan">Maintenance Tips</string>
    <string name="penyebab_wilt_and_leaf_blight">Wilt and leaf blight infections in plants are caused by various pathogens, such as Fusarium sp. and Cercospora sp. fungi. The disease can be spread through soil, water, wind, as well as through contact with infected plants or unsterilised farm tools. Wilt is a condition in which the plant loses turgour or stiffness of the cells, so that the leaves and stems appear wilted and sagging. The main cause of wilt is infection by pathogens that attack the plant\'s vascular system, such as Verticillium or Fusarium fungi, which block the flow of water and nutrients within the plant. Early symptoms include wilting of the young leaves and shoots of the plant, which then spreads to the rest of the plant, causing defoliation and plant death if not treated promptly.</string>
    <string name="penanganan_wilt_and_leaf_blight">1. Prune the infected leaves to help the plant grow better.\n2. Regularly clean hydroponic growing areas, such as containers and watering pipes.\n3. Use fungicides to control fungal infections.</string>
    <string name="penyebab_viral">Viral infections in plants are caused by various types of viruses that spread through insect vectors, such as aphids or thrips, or through direct contact between infected and healthy plants. Viruses can cause a variety of symptoms in plants, depending on the type of virus and the infected plant. Viral infections often result in plant leaves having yellow or mottled spots, known as mosaic. In addition, leaves may become curled, shriveled or deformed. If a viral infection progresses, the virus can spread to all parts of the plant, including the stem, which can lead to stunted growth and deformed leaves.</string>
    <string name="penanganan_viral">1. There is no direct treatment for plants already infected with the virus, but the use of insecticides can help reduce the spread of virus-carrying pests.\n2. Separate infected plants to prevent further spread.</string>
    <string name="penyebab_powdery_mildew">Caused by various types of fungi in the Erysiphaceae family. The spread of these fungi is mainly through wind-borne spores. flowers, and fruit. Early symptoms are characterised by powdery white patches on the lower and upper surfaces of leaves. Infected leaves may turn yellow and die. Powdery mildew thrives in warm and dry climates/weather.</string>
    <string name="penanganan_powdery_mildew">1. Remove infected plants from the growing environment.\n2. Remove infected leaves to reduce the spread of the disease.\n3. Provide a minimum distance of 30-45 cm between plants to increase air circulation in plants.\n4. Spray Fungicide such as sulphur in 7-14 days interval to provide continuous protection to the plants.</string>
    <string name="penyebab_downy_mildew">Caused by infection with the fungus Bremia lactucae, the spores of this fungus are spread by rain or air. This causes the leaves to have bright yellowish-green spots on the upper part of the leaf, while on the underside fine cotton-like hairs of a bluish-white colour grow. If allowed to develop, the fungus will penetrate into the stem which can cause the stem to rot.</string>
    <string name="penangan_downy_mildew">1. Remove infected plants from the growing environment.\n2. Avoid watering from above which may cause the leaf surface to become wet.\n3. Increase air circulation to reduce plant humidity and provide adequate lighting.\n4. Avoid dense planting and control weeds, so that air circulation around the plants remains good.</string>
    <string name="penyebab_bacterial">"Bacterial is caused by bacterial infections such as Erwinia Carotovora, Felicularia F, Rhizoctonia S or Xanthomonas spp. These bacteria can be spread through rain, splashing water, insects, or direct contact between infected and healthy plants.  The optimum temperature for infection is 73°F (23°C). However, the disease occurs at warmer temperatures on lettuce grown in greenhouses. Bacterial blight often affects the leaves of plants with the appearance of small brown spots surrounded by a yellow halo, which over time can develop into large irregular blotches. "</string>
    <string name="penenganan_bacterial">1. Arrange the planting distance so that the outer leaves do not touch.\n2. Provide adequate lighting, with direct sunlight for at least 4-6 hours per day.\n3. Remove infected leaves to reduce the spread of the disease.\n4. Spray with pesticides containing copper hydroxide or a mixture of copper and mankozeb at intervals of 3-5 days.</string>
    <string name="penyebab_septoria_blight">Caused by the pathogen Septoria Lactucae, the disease spreads again through water, wind, insect transmission, weeds around the plant, or even through human hands or tools. Infected leaves have light brown coloured spots that appear between the leaf veins. Affected leaves may dry out and become thin.</string>
    <string name="penenganan_septoria_blight">1. Remove seedlings that show leaf spots before transplanting to hydroponic media.\n2. Avoid wetting the leaves by watering from above.\n3. Clear the weeds around the plants.\n4. Increase adequate air circulation.\n5. Spray the plants with copper-based fungicides such as copper diammonia diacetate.</string>
    <string name="tips_merawat_selada">Lettuce Care Tips</string>
    <string name="penyebab">Causes</string>
    <string name="pengendalian">Control</string>
    <string name="bahasa">Language</string>
    <string name="ubah_bahasa">Available languages are only Indonesian and English</string>
    <string name="tentang">About</string>
    <string name="tentang_aplikasi">About the App</string>
    <string name="kembali">Back</string>
    <string name="cara_mengobati">How to Treat:</string>
    <string name="gejala_penyakit">Disease Symptoms:</string>
    <string name="apa_yang_ingin_anda_ketahui">What do you want to know?</string>
    <string name="tolong_masukan_foto_terlebih_dahulu">Please Insert a Photo First</string>
    <string name="akurasi">\nAccuracy:  </string>
    <string name="nama">"Name: "</string>
    <string name="see_more">See More</string>
    <string name="our_teams">Our Team</string>
    <string name="data_tersimpan_message">Data has already been saved</string>
    <string name="team">Team</string>
    <string name="member_of_team">Member Of Team</string>
    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="about">Inspired by Indonesia\'s agricultural landscape and the rising popularity of hydroponic gardening, HICARE addresses the critical need for efficient plant health management by developing a mobile application utilizing advanced image classification technology. Focused on detecting diseases in hydroponic lettuce, the app provides users with real-time identification of color and shape changes in plant leaves, coupled with comprehensive maintenance guidance and treatment strategies. This innovative solution aims to empower hydroponic enthusiasts and agricultural stakeholders alike, ensuring enhanced crop yield quality through accessible and accurate plant care management</string>
    <string name="about_app">About App</string>
    <string name="specialist_text">Ask to Kiana, our specialist Lettuce</string>

</resources>